Finding Aid for Martha Louise Kinsey Olmsted papers, 1972-1976
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Martha Louise Kinsey Olmsted papers 1972-1976
Olmsted, Martha Louise Kinsey
1 linear foot
861070 Aa 2
Doctoral student in educational gerontology at the Institute of Gerontology of the University of Michigan. Class notes and other materials received from her course work in psychology, social work, and education; and other collected material on topic of aging.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was transferred from the University of Michigan Institute of Gerontology (donor no. 6160 ) in October 1984.
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
Martha Olmsted was a doctoral student in Educational Gerontology at the University of Michigan.
The Martha Olmsted collection relates primarily to her education at the University of Michigan and to her professional interests. Included are syllabi, handouts, notebooks, and essays for graduate school courses in psychology, social work, and education (including extensive teaching aids for student teaching of a secondary school social studies class); handouts and notes from two special short-term programs in gerontology, one at the University of Southern California and one on milieu therapy at the Institute of Gerontology at the University of Michigan; Olmsted's dissertation along with some supporting documents; and scattered documents from the Washtenaw County Council on Aging (WCCOA), and the Hand-in-Hand Cross Age Program for Girl Scouts in Oakland County.
Subjects:
Aging.; Gerontology.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Psychology.; University of Michigan. School of Education.; University of Michigan. School of Social Work.; University of Michigan--Student notebooks.; Washtenaw County Council on Aging.
- Course Work
  - 1972, Psychology 758 (Psychological Processes in Aging); Social Work 698 (Programs and Services for the Aged)
    - Syllabi and Handouts (Box 1)
    - Notebook (Box 1)
    - Papers (Box 1)
  - 1973, C701 (Psychology of Aging): Syllabi, notes, papers (Box 1)
  - 1973, Unidentified course; Papers and secondary material (Box 1)
  - 1973, Education 490 (Social Studies Method/Student Teaching): Course handouts and teaching tools, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - 1974, Education H652 (Workshop in Human Resources in Adult and Continuing Education): Papers by all class members (Box 1)
  - 1975, Education H510 (Educational Gerontology): Syllabi and Handouts (Box 1)
  - 1976, University Course 448 (Late Style in Art, Literature, and Music): Syllabi, notebook, handouts (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous syllabi and papers (Box 1)
- Special Study
  - 1974, Summer Institute for Study in Gerontology, USC: Notes, syllabi, handouts (Box 1)
  - 1975, IOG (Institute of Gerontology), 5-day Workshop in Milieu Therapy
    - Course Materials (Box 1)
    - Notes (Box 1)
- Dissertation, 1976
  - Typescript, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Background Material
    - "A Unit on Aging for High School Curriculum," Marcia J. Cameron, IOG (Box 1)
    - "Effect of a Unit of Gerontology on Secondary School Students," Dissertation-in Educational Gerontology, University of Michigan, Karl M. Pelton (Box 1)
    - "Education on Aging for Teachers," Education 300, Martha Olmsted (Box 1)
- Extra-Curricular Work in Gerontology
  - Washtenaw County Council on Aging (WCCOA)
    - Statement of Purpose, Minutes, Grants, Governmental Liaison Papers, 1971-1973 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, ca. 1973 (Box 1)
  - Hand-in-Hand: Cross Age Program for Girl Scouts in Oakland County, ca. 1976 (Box 1)